domu.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Statement

Thank you for visiting Domu.com.  We appreciate that you trust us as a partner in your search for a new place to call home, if you are renter, or in your search for a tenant, if you are a landlord.  We value your privacy.  Please read this **Privacy Statement** to understand our information gathering practices and your ability to selectively opt out. 

**You consent to the information collection, usage, disclosure, and storage practiced described in this Privacy Statement when you use the Domu website.**

**Why does Domu collect personal information from its users?**

Domu collects information from users in order to make the housing search process more personal and efficient. 

**What information does Domu collect from its users?**

Some information you provide to us automatically, and other information you provide in order to utilize certain features of our website.  Any information that you provide to us we may collect.  For example, we might collect information about the type of apartment that interests you.

  * **Automatic Information:** When you visit the Domu website, you disclose your IP address and certain information about your computing, such as the type of browser and operating system you are using and the page that referred you to our site.  
  * **Mobile Information:   **When you use Domu’s mobile site, you have the option to disclose your location to Domu.  Domu collects this information only after you give explicit permission for Domu to do so. 
  * **Information You Provide to Domu:**  To take advantage of certain functionalities offered by the website, you will need to supply additional information.  For example, 
    * To save your searches, you must share your e-mail address and create a password;
    * To contact a landlord about a listing, you must share your e-mail address;
    * To send a listing to a friend, you must share your e-mail address as well as your friend’s;
    * To post an apartment for rent, you must share an e-mail address, create a password, and provide a valid credit card number with name and billing address.

Any e-mail addresses and passwords received through Domu and stored by Domu are encrypted. This includes not only your own e-mail address, but any other address that you transmit through a web form. 

**Does Domu Share the Information it Receives?**

Domu does not sell any of the information that it receives from its users.

Domu shares information when it is directed by you to do so.  For example, if you use a Domu web form to share a listing with a friend or to contact a landlord, any information you place in the web form will be visible to that friend or landlord.

Any information that you supply in the course of a credit card transaction is transmitted to our payment processor, Chase Paymentech, through its orbital payment gateway using Secure Socket Layer technology.  Chase Paymentech is subject to the detailed rules and regulations of the various credit and debit card organizations and networks relating to the security and safeguarding of cardholder data, including the payment card industry data security standards (PCI DSS).  For more on this, please visit Chase Paymentech, scroll to the bottom of the page and click on the link to its privacy policy.  Credit card numbers are not stored with Domu, although Domu maintains the name and address associated with the credit card, as well as the transaction amount and transaction identification number.  Domu may access credit card numbers through the Orbital payment gateway, but those numbers remain with the payment processor.

**How does Domu use the information it collects?**

Any time you supply an e-mail address (or a friend’s e-mail address), Domu may use it to communicate with you about matters believed to be of interest to you.  Should Domu ever do so, it will provide you the opportunity to opt out of future communications.

Domu may also use your e-mail address to communicate with you regarding specific transactions you engage in on the site.  For example:

Whenever you establish an account, Domu will send you an e-mail confirming that the account has been created.

If you save a search, Domu will periodically alert you to newly-listed Chicago apartments matching your search criteria, although you have the option to set preferences on how often you would like to be notified of new search results, including the preference not to be contacted at all.

If you activate a listing for a Chicago apartment, Domu will confirm the receipt of your credit card payment and may later alert you when your listing is about to expire or remind you of your ability to renew it.

If you choose to share your location when using Domu’s mobile feature, Domu will use your location to data to show you listings in the vicinity. 

Domu might also utilize your search history in order to serve you advertisements that meet your requirements (see “Marketing,” below).

Domu does not accept advertisements (other than listings) and does not disclose e-mail addresses to third-parties, subject to the exceptions set forth in the next paragraph.

Notwithstanding anything contained herein to the contrary, Domu reserves the right to disclose any data or information in its possession (or to use your e-mail address) when required by law or legal process or when Domu believes in good faith that such disclosure (or use) is necessary to  _(i)_  enforce the terms of service,  _(ii)_  respond to claims that any user-generated content violates the rights of third-parties, or  _(iii)_  protect the safety or property of Domu, its users, or members of the public.

**Cookies and Google Analytics**

A HTTP cookie is an identifier that a website transfers to the user’s computer or mobile device and that is stored in the user’s web browser.  Domu uses cookies to identify the user and enhance the user experience, and also to understand the way in which the website is used.  If you object to Domu’s use of cookies, look to your browser’s help feature for information about how to disable or clear cookies.

Domu also uses Google Analytics as a tool for tracking and analyzing its web traffic.  Google Analytics runs on the Domu server and uses a combination of first-party cookies and Javascript code to compile information that is synthesized into reports about page visits, referring sites, user habits, and the like.  Google is not provided access to any user information other than IP addresses.  

Google has created an “Opt-out Browser Add-on” for users who wish to use websites while preventing their data from being accessed or used by Google Analytics.  If you want to opt out of the features on Domu.com that rely on Google Analytics, please follow the directions provided by Google here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/> features

**Marketing**

Domu uses Google’s “remarketing” service to advertise Domu on the Internet.  Google’s remarketing service allows Domu to show users advertisements that are specifically tailored to them based on their prior usage of Domu. For example, if a user searches on Domu for two-bedroom apartments in Lincoln Square, Domu’s remarketing campaign might cause that user to see an advertisement on a third party website for a Domu listing of a two-bedroom apartment in Lincoln Square. These advertisements might appear on a Google search result page, or on a site in the Google Display network. 

The remarketing service relies on cookies placed on your computer or mobile device.  The cookie does not identify you or give access to your device, nor does it collect any personally identifiable information such as an e-mail address, name, or any credit card information.  The cookie simply identifies which types of listings or services interested you in the past, so that Domu may show you advertisements about those listings or services in the future.   Domu utilizes this type of marketing in order to show you only the advertisements that are relevant to you. 

You may opt-out of Google’s remarketing services by visiting [https://privacy.google.com. ](https://privacy.google.com.%20/) You may also opt out of Interest-Based Advertising by visiting <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.

**Security**

E-mail addresses, passwords, credit card information, messages transmitted in web forms, and other user-generated content of a confidential nature in Domu’s possession will be accessible only to authorized personnel at Domu.  The Domu website is hosted at Rackspace, and Domu cannot guarantee that information will not be intercepted from the website or that security breaches will not occur.

This Privacy Statement applies solely to your dealings with Domu.  Once you leave the Domu domain, your online actions will be subject to the privacy policy, if any, of the new website you enter, even if you reached that website by following a link from Domu.  This Privacy Statement may be updated from time-to-time, and Domu recommends that you periodically revisit this page to keep yourself apprised of any changes.
